deeprootsathome.com 2018-12-20

# Privacy Policy - Deep Roots at Home

In a world full of digital interactions and relationships, we never want to forget that we are interacting with real people who have real rights!

Your privacy matters to us at Deep Roots at Home. This policy reflects how we collect, protect, and use your personal information.

## 1.INTRODUCTION

This privacy notice provides you with details of how we collect and process your personal data through your use of our site [deeprootsathome.com](https://deeprootsathome.com/).

By providing us with your data, you warrant to us that you are over 13 years of age.

Deep Roots LLC is the data controller and we are responsible for your personal data (referred to as “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice).

**Contact Details**

Our full details are these:  
**Full name of legal entity:** Deep Roots LLC  
**Email address:** [no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com](mailto:no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com)  
**Postal address:** PO Box 14, Maxwell, IN, 46154 , USA

It is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if at any time your personal information changes by emailing us at [no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com](mailto:no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com).

## 2\. WHAT DATA DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU, FOR WHAT PURPOSE AND ON WHAT GROUND WE PROCESS IT

Personal data means any information capable of identifying an individual. It does not include anonymized data.

We may process the following categories of personal data about you:

**Communication Data** that includes any communication that you send to us whether that be through social media messaging, social media posting or any other communication that you send us. We process this data for the purposes of communicating with you, for record keeping and for the establishment, pursuance or defense of legal claims. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to reply to communications sent to us, to keep records and to establish, pursue or defend legal claims.

**User Data** that includes data about how you use our website and any online services together with any data that you post for publication on our website (such as blog comments) or through other online services. We process this data to operate our website and ensure relevant content is provided to you, to ensure the security of our website, to maintain back-ups of our website and/or databases and to enable publication and administration of our website, other online services and business. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to enable us to properly administer our website and our ministry/business.

**Technical Data** that includes data about your use of our website and online services such as your IP address, details about your browser, length of visit to pages on our website, page views and navigation paths, details about the number of times you use our website, time zone settings and other technology on the devices you use to access our website. The source of this data is from our analytics tracking system. We process this data to analyze your use of our website and other online services, to administer and protect our business and website, to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and to understand the effectiveness of our advertising. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to enable us to properly administer our website and our ministry/business and to grow our influence and to decide our outreach strategy.

**Marketing Data** that includes data about your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences. We process this data to enable you to partake in our promotions such as competitions, prize drawings and free give-aways, to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of this advertising. Our lawful ground for this processing is our legitimate interests which in this case are to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our influence and to decide our outreach strategy.

We may use User Data, Technical Data and Marketing Data to deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you (including Facebook advertisements or other display advertisements) and to measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve you. Our lawful ground for this processing is legitimate interests which is to grow our ministry/business. We may also use such data to send other marketing communications to you. Our lawful ground for this processing is either consent or legitimate interests (namely to grow our influence).

**Sensitive Data:  **We do not collect any Sensitive Data about you. Sensitive data refers to data that includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data. We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offenses.

We will only use your personal data for a purpose it was collected for or a reasonably compatible purpose if necessary. For more information on this please email us at [no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com](mailto:no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com). 

We may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent where this is required or permitted by law.

## 3\. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We may collect data about you by you providing the data directly to us (for example by leaving a comment on our blog, subscribing to emails, or by sending us emails). We may automatically collect certain data from you as you use our website by using cookies and similar technologies. Please [see our cookie policy](https://deeprootsathome.com/cookie-policy) for more details about this.

For those based in the EU: We are based in the United States. We may receive data from third parties such as analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU, advertising networks such as Facebook based outside the EU, such as search information providers such as Google based outside the EU, providers of technical, payment and delivery services, such as data brokers or aggregators.

If you complete a survey or questionnaire, we may collect the following personal data: Your identity, contact details, profile data, usage practices of our website, marketing and/or communication details. Our legal grounds for processing your data is our legitimate interests in understanding how customers and readers use our site, products, and services in order to better develop our ministry/business strategy.

**Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us.**

## 4\. MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS

Our lawful ground of processing your personal data to send you marketing communications is either your consent or our legitimate interests (namely to grow our ministry/business).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested to receive information or emails, from us, if you provided us with your details and have agreed that we send you email marketing communication, and have not unsubscribed from our emails.

You can ask us to stop sending you emails and marketing messages at any time by following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or by emailing us at [no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com](mailto:no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com).

**We do not share your personal identifiable data with any third party for their own marketing purposes.**

## 5\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below:

  * Service providers who provide website, IT, and system administration services
  * Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers
  * Government bodies that require us to report processing activities
  * Third parties to whom we sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets (we do not currently have plans for this)

We require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

## 6\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

At times your personal data may be transferred data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

We are subject to the provisions of the General Data Protection Regulations that protect your personal data. Where we transfer your data to third parties outside of the EEA, we will ensure that certain safeguards are in place to ensure a similar degree of security for your personal data.

The hosting facilities for our website are situated in The United States. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission.

You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.

Here are the third parties from which we may receive data about you:

  * Technical data from [MailerLite](https://www.mailerlite.com/privacy-policy)
  * Advertising network: [Mediavine Marketing](https://www.mediavinemarketing.com/privacy-policy/)
  * Social media platforms: [Facebook / Instagram](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/en/privacy), [Pinterest](https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy),
  * Social media scheduling platform: [Tailwind](https://www.tailwindapp.com/about/privacy)
  * Analytics provided by [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy)

## 7\. DATA SECURITY

We have security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used, altered, disclosed, or accessed without authorization. We also allow access to your personal data only to those employees and partners who have a business need to know such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they must keep it confidential.

## 8\. DATA RETENTION

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal or reporting requirements.

When deciding what the correct time is to keep the data for we look at its amount, nature and sensitivity, potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure, the processing purposes, if these can be achieved by other means and legal requirements.

In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal data for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

## 9\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

If you are protected by the EU/EEA GDPR, under these data protection laws, you have rights in relation to your personal data that include the right to request access, correction, erasure, restriction, transfer, to object to processing, to portability of data and (where the lawful ground of processing is consent) to withdraw consent.

You can see more about these rights at <https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/>

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please email us at [no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com](mailto:no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com).

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive or refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you.

If you are not happy with any aspect of how we collect and use your data, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/)). We would be grateful if you would contact us first if you do have a complaint so that we can try to resolve it for you.

## 10\. THIRD-PARTY LINKS

This website includes links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

Deep Roots at Home may divulge personal information to certain and specific third parties for the reasons laid out in this privacy policy. Those third parties are:

  * Services Providers: Those who assist us in offering support for our website, such as through website hosting and email delivery.
  * Advertising: We may partner with third-party advertisers, such as listed above. Some third-party advertisers use cookies when advertising on our website and may transfer information incoming your IP address, your ISP, your browser used, and perhaps if you have installed Flash. This may enable them to show ads relevant to your needs and searches.

## 11\. COOKIES

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please [see our cookie policy](https://deeprootsathome.com/cookie-policy).

## 12\. CALIFORNIA-SPECIFIC POLICIES

**Do Not Track Signals:** Regarding the California Online Privacy Protection Act, we hereby disclose that we do not currently intentionally honor “do not track” signals issued by browsers or other third party sources.

**California Eraser Law** : If you are an individual under 18 and have provided personal information or content to us in some manner, you have the right to request the deletion of that information pursuant to the “California Eraser Law.” Email your request to [no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com](mailto:no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com). For your protection we may request that you verify your identity. 

## 13\. CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

We may update this Privacy Policy updated periodically without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices or updates to our ministry/business. Unless otherwise stated, any such updates are effective immediately. We will indicate in the notice when it was most recently updated. 

## 14\. CONTACT US

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, or any of our other policies or disclosures, you may contact us at [no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com](mailto:no.reply.deep.roots.at.home@gmail.com).

Effective May 25, 2018.
